hey everybody welcome to this a2
english listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening and comprehension
as i speak remember to sign up for our
one dollar listening practice seminars
at polyglossa polyglossa.com
and download our free listening time
podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills
[Music]
so today i'm going to talk about
neighborhoods
i think this is an interesting topic
because neighborhoods
look and function differently in
different countries
specifically i want to talk about
american neighborhoods
and even more specifically i want to
focus on residential neighborhoods
such as the suburbs in the u.s i would
say that most people have the goal to
eventually live in a house in a
residential neighborhood
sure some people prefer living in
apartments
in the city but i still think that most
people still want to buy a house someday
when they have enough money
so living in a house in a suburb is very
common
in the u.s i spent my whole childhood
living in
residential areas in southern california
so i have a lot of experience in these
types of neighborhoods
so what are some of the distinct
elements of american neighborhoods
first of all there's a pretty distinct
american style
of houses of course our houses often
have
triangular roofs you've probably seen
this in movies and tv
shows american houses also have a garage
a driveway a front yard and a backyard
houses in other countries might not have
all these different elements
but in the u.s these features are all
really popular
what's interesting for some foreigners
is that in the u.s
houses often don't have fences in their
front yards
this means that when you're in your
front yard you can easily see
and interact with your neighbors this
might seem uncomfortable
but it does help neighbors be friendly
with each other
however in backyards there are always
fences
or gates this area is a little more
private
kids normally play in their backyard
front yard
or in the street if the neighborhood
isn't that busy
typically residential neighborhoods are
pretty safe in the u.s
so kids can play outside without parents
worrying too much
but parents do need to keep an eye on
their kids just to be safe
for kids it's really common to make
friends with the other kids in the
neighborhood
i remember when i was growing up that i
always played with my neighbors
i actually became good friends with them
in other countries
it's common to see children playing
soccer in the street
in different neighborhoods but in the us
it's more
common to see kids playing other sports
or games
now let's talk a little bit about being
a good neighbor
in the u.s it's really important to have
respect for your neighbors
for example it's not acceptable to play
really loud music
or have loud parties at night if you do
this
after 10 pm your neighbors will probably
call the police
this is extremely common in the us
because police
actually respond to these noise
complaints
they show up at your house and tell you
to be quiet
or you'll be in trouble also in many
neighborhoods
you're expected to maintain your house
and
front yard well people don't like it
when their neighbor's house
or front yard looks ugly or neglected
this can actually make the neighboring
houses less
valuable on the other hand one of the
great things about
residential neighborhoods in the u.s is
the sense of community
traditionally people are friendly and
helpful
in these types of areas for example if
you move to a suburb
it's very common for your neighbors to
bring you over
some homemade food and welcome you to
the neighborhood
also people help each other out in these
neighborhoods
for instance if you go on vacation it's
common to ask your neighbors
to keep an eye on your house and even
water your plants
or things like that the sense of
community is definitely a big
positive of living in residential
neighborhoods
in the us alright now i'm going to ask
you some questions about today's video
to see how well you understood number
one
what shape is the typical american roof
number two do american houses have
fences
in the front yard or backyard and number
three
in the u.s what might happen if you make
a lot of noise at night
okay remember to sign up for our one
dollar listening practice seminars
and download the listening time podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills
also don't forget to subscribe to the
channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram
i'll see you next time
[Music]